dollarclix.com 2019-08-12

# DollarClix - Members - Privacy Policy

Opinion Capital Inc. (the "Company") owns and operates DollarClix.com. The Company is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its user community and here at DollarClix we take your privacy and the processing of your personal data very seriously. Therefore, we have prepared this Privacy Notice where we describe our contact details, information regarding what personal data we process and what rights you have towards us and how you may defend them. Always feel free to contact our customer support if you have any questions about our processing of personal data or this Privacy Notice.

### Contact Details to the Controller

Name of the company: Opinion Capital Inc  
National company registration number: 74233 1523  
VAT number: 74233 1523 RT0001  
Country of operation: Canada  
E-mail address: privacy@opinioncapital.com  
Phone number: +1 514 217 1875  
Postal address: Saint-Lazare, Quebec, Canada, J7T 3B4  
E-mail address to customer support: support@dollarclix.com  

### Contact details for the Controllers representative:

Name: Vincent Dupuy  
Title: Personal Data Responsible  
E-mail address: privacy@opinioncapital.com  
Phone number: +1 514 217 1875  

* * *

### What is personal data?

"Personal data" is any information relating to an identifiable or identified person (you as a user). An identifiable person is someone who can be identified, directly or indirectly, for example by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his or her physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.

The processing of special categories of data, defined as personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, and of data concerning health or sex life, is prohibited, subject to certain exceptions. 

### Personal data which we handle

The processing of the personal data, the specific purposes for the processing, the legal basis for the processing are described below, and for how long we store your personal data is described below. 

#### Email address

We collect and process your email address to validate that the user entering our system is a real person. We do this as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Address

We collect and process your address (only postal code, state, region and country) as most surveys are geo-targeted to respondents from specific locations. We do this as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Date of Birth

As most surveys are targeting respondents based on age, we collect and process your date of birth/age, as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Professional Details

Many surveys are targeted to specific professional profiles. Therefore, we collect and process your professional details as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Profiling Details

For statistical reasons, many surveys require profiling details (including gender, highest completed level of education, occupation, marital status and annual/monthly income). We therefore collect and process this personal data as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Event registration details

Some survey creators collect event registration details, and this is therefore collected and processed by us, as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

#### Special categories of personal data

On rare occasions, survey creators ask for any of the here specified special categories of personal data. This means religious/philosophical belief, race and ethnicity, political opinion, sex life, and sexual orientation. Therefore, we collect and process such information, as it is necessary for our performance of a contract where you as a user are a party.

Cookies

Upon your first visit to DollarClix, a cookie is sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. A "cookie" is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website.

We use cookies to improve the quality of our service and to better understand how people interact with us. DollarClix does this by storing user preferences in cookies and by tracking user trends and patterns of how people access our site.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some DollarClix features or services may not function properly without cookies.

* * *

All of the personal data which we collect/process is stored by us for as long as you as a user are active and is automatically deleted when you have been inactive for six (6) months. All profiling details described above are always deleted after six (6) months and must be re-entered by you.

DollarClix may share your personal information and/or social-demographic information, including, without limitation, a unique identification number ("UID"), postal code, region, province, gender, marital status, education, ethnicity/race (where permitted by applicable law), employment related information, non-personally identifiable information on household members, consumer product and service usage and ownership (e.g., computers, cars, mobile devices, video games, etc.), home ownership, pet ownership, employment information (e.g., title, role, travel, industry, etc.), and social grade, with third party sample/market research companies (individually each a "Third Party MR Company" and collectively the "Third Party MR Companies") for the following purposes:

  * Identifying client survey opportunities that you may be eligible for through the Third Party MR Companies; and
  * Disclosing such data elements to clients of the Third Party MR Companies for audience measurement services; and
  * Appending such data elements to completed client surveys and delivering the appended survey data to clients of the Third Party MR Company(ies) for analytical or research purposes; and

  * Other uses as set forth in their privacy policy.

If you are eligible for a client survey opportunity offered through a Third Party MR Company, the Third Party MR Company will provide your unique identification number and a survey link to us and we will invite you to participate in the client survey through a router link, a survey wall or by email you subscribed to. We will not share your name, email address, or phone number with the Third Party MR Companies. In connection with the sharing of your information with a Third Party MR Company, your information may be transferred and stored outside of your country of residence, including, without limitation, in the United States, and by agreeing to this privacy policy you are agreeing to the processing and exportation of your personal information as set forth in this Section.

If you have any questions about this data sharing please contact support@dollarclix.com or you can opt-out by sending [Support Ticket](http://http//dollarclix.com/members/ticket.php) t us. If you opt-out, it is the responsibility of us to inform the Third Party MR Companies. Please note that DollarClix is solely liable and responsible for managing all opt-out requests. Your participation in such survey opportunities does not entitle you to any benefits offered by, or membership with, the Third Party MR Companies.

* * *

### Summary of your rights towards us:

You as a user have the possibility to claim several rights towards us. Such rights are listed here and thereafter described in detail below. You find our contact details at the top of this Privacy Notice.

  * Right to be forgotten
  * Right to withdraw consent
  * Right to access
  * Right to rectification
  * Right to restriction of processing
  * Right to data portability
  * Right to object
  * Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

#### Right to be forgotten

You have the right to request that we delete any personal data that we process about you. We will delete the data as soon as possible, but at least within one months time. If the personal data is needed for fulfillment of our contractual duties towards you or to preserve it with legal ground, we will however not delete the information until the data is no longer needed. We will also, without your explicit demand, delete such personal data that we have collected but do not longer have a lawful right to process. We will inform you about this, if it would occur.

#### Right to withdraw consent

You have, at any time, the right to receive confirmation from us as to whether personal data concerning you are being processed. You have also the right to access that personal data and to receive the following information:

  * The purposes of the processing
  * The categories of personal data concerned
  * The recipients or categories of recipients to whom personal data have been or will be disclosed
  * The envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored or the criteria used to determine that period
  * The existence of automated decision-making and profiling

#### Right to rectification

You have, at any time, the right to demand us to correct any inaccurate personal data within a months time. You have also the right to complete incomplete personal data, taking into account our purposes of the processing, by the means of providing a supplementary statement. 

#### Right to restriction of processing

You have, instead of demanding us to delete any data, the right to demand us to restrict our processing of your personal data. This may be achieved if

  * a) You have reason to believe that the accuracy of the personal data is not correct, and the restriction shall be in place during a period that allows us to verify the accuracy of the personal data
  * b) The processing is unlawful but you dont want us to delete the personal data
  * c) We no longer need the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they are required by you for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims
  * d) You have objected to processing concerning profiling or automated decision-making, whereby a restriction shall be obtained during the period when we assess whether our legitimate ground for the processing override your legitimate ground.

#### Data portability

You have the right to receive the personal data concerning you that you have provided to us. The personal data is obtainable in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You also have the right to transmit such personal data to another data controller if the personal data is collected based on your consent or if the processing of the personal data is carried out by automated means. If we deem it technically feasible, you have the right to us transmitting the personal data to another controller.

#### Right to object

You have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you. This can be done when the personal data is processed as part of automated decision-making, including profiling, and direct marketing, if such processing would be carried out (see "Personal data that we process above).

#### Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

You have, at any time, the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority regarding our processing of your personal data. Regardless of where we carry out our business, even if it would not be in the member state which is your country of residence, you have the right to lodge your complaint to your national supervisory authority. Please follow to the link below to find the contact details to your national supervisory authority:

<http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>

* * *

### About this Privacy Notice

With regard to the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 ("GDPR), we must disclose what personal data we collect and process about you, and for what purposes. In this Privacy Notice, you find all such information that we are obliged to inform you.

The Regulation in its entirety in your language, may be accessed by following this link:

[http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG&toc=OJ:L:2016:119:TOC](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG&toc=OJ:L:2016:119:TOC)

Would you like to defend your rights, which are listed in this Privacy Notice, you may contact us using the contact information listed above.

Please note this Privacy Policy will change from time to time. We expect most such changes to be minor, but there may be changes that are more significant. Regardless, we will post those changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will also provide a more prominent notice on our News Page. Each version will be noted at the top of the page.

Your Consent  
By using our site, you consent to our Privacy Policy.
